# Amha Kindu

I am a developer with over 4 years of experience in python and various other tech stacks. I have worked on various web development projects in my career, spanning from backend frameworks like ASP .NET, Nestjs, Flask, Django and FastAPI to frontend development with vanilla Html, CSS, Javascript and React.

King George VI st. Addis Ababa, 5 kilo, Ethiopia +251978259900 amhakindu@gmail.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Eskalate Africa Software Development S.C

4 kilo, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia — Backend Developer

MARCH 2023 - JUNE 2023

Worked on with C#\.NET, ridesharing algorithms, clean architecture

Freelancing on Upwork,

Remote — Full Stack Python Developer

APRIL 2023 - PRESENT

Worked on projects with Django, FastAPI, React, Flask

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Addis Ababa Institute of Technology**

5 kilo, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia — Degree

JANUARY 2019 - PRESENT

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering

(Artificial Intelligence Specialization)

## **PROJECTS**

## **Machine Translation** — English to Amharic Language Translation

Trained a custom LLM model based on "Attention is all you need" paper

https://www.github.com/amha-kindu/machine-translation

## **NFT Marketplace** — *Platform to trade NFTs*

Blockchain powered web application with C#/.NET and Clean Architecture

https://github.com/amha-kindu/balthazar

#### **SKILLS**

Python, FastAPI, Flask, Django, Machine Learning(Pytorch, Numpy, Pandas, Tensorflow, Sklearn)

Java, C/C++, C#, .NET

Html, css, Javascript, Typescript, Reactjs, Nestjs

MVC, Clean and Microservice Architectures

MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Apache Kafka

Github/Git

#### **LANGUAGES**

English(Fluent)

Amharic(Native)